Victor Owiti Software Developer

- https://github.com/vicowiti
- Pusia, Kenya, 50404 Busia, Kenya
- ≥ viowiti12@gmail.com
- +254706770684
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/victor-owiti/
- https://viowiti.netlify.app/

Profile

User-centered design and development is my forte. Ensuring the needs of the user are transformed into working solutions. I love to challenge myself every day, learn new technologies, and to see a project grow from an idea to a problem-solving product or feature. Literal chills!

Projects

VDial ecommerce

Tech Stack: NextJS, Sanity, Tailwind CSS

A React JS app for a huawei reseller. Managed cart state using React context API and styling using Tailwind CSS. Also worked with Sanity CMS to manage product inventory.

Golds Gym, A home alternative to your local gym ☑

Tech Stack: Reactjs, Material UI

- A React application harnessing the ExerciseDB API.
- Ability to search for exercises by name, equipment, and body parts.
- Shows youtube videos of related exercises.
- GIF images showing instances of the exercise.

Languages & Tools

• Git	 HTML/CSS 	 ReactJs/React Native

- NodeJs
 Express
 MongoDb
- Typescript/Javascript
 Tailwind Css
 Python

Professional Experience

09/2022 - 12/2022	The Collab Lab, Frontend Developer (Intern) ☑
Remote	 Worked in a team of 4 developers in a European/African team to build a smart shopping list application that learns about your purchases over time and recommends items on every visit to the store. Used agile methodologies to ensure the project was on track via code reviews and weekly sprints.
10/2018 - 01/2022	Top Image Africa, Brand Ambassador

- Increased gross adds in my cluster by 20%.
 - Maintained a steady increase of Safaricom service revenue of 3% p.a.

Education

Busia, Kenya

01/2022 – present	University of the People, BSc Computer Science
06/2021 - 07/2022	ALX - Holberton, Software Engineering
Busia, Kenya	• C programming, Python, SQL, Javascript